Tamikurasou
A
Please be quiet
when climbing the
stairs.
Landlord.
Tamikurasou
A
Water
（阿良々木(あららぎ)）
戦場ヶ原(せんじょうがはら)の家は豪邸だって
Hanekawa mentioned that you were living in a luxurious house, Senjougahara...
羽川(はねかわ)は言ってたけど
A
One match leads to fire
Be careful with fire
My mom got immersed in a cult.
（戦場ヶ原）
母親が怪しい宗教に
はまってしまってね
All the valuables in our house were given to them.
財産を全て
貢いだどころじゃ済まなくて
She also incurred a huge debt.
多額の借金まで背負ってしまって
Therefore, my parents voluntarily divorced toward the end of last year.
結局 去年の暮れに
協議離婚が成立して
My father has custody of me, and we have both lived here since then.
私は お父さんに引き取られ
ここで２人で暮らしているわ
I can still yet make it on time,
ima nara mada ma ni au kara
so I might as well get out.
tekkai shita hou ga ii yo
Before I'm even more wrong.
motto kanchigai shiteshimau mae ni
staple stable
The staples of the words that bound you
kimi wo tojita kotoba no hari
Just when was it that you
itsu no ma ni ka
pierced this heart of mine?
kono mune ni sasatte shimatteita
It hurts
itai
I guess it was your fault
kimi no sei da na
Don't come, near me.
konaide, konna konna watashi wo
Don't look, to that, that place
minaide, sonna sonna toko made
Don't talk, with that, that smiling face
hanasanaide, anna anna egao de
Whatever, with whomever,
donna, dare ni mo,
I'll continue on anywhere
doko made de mo tsuzuku
in this sky
kono sora no you na
like an eternity
owari no nai eien mo chikatte
without an end, I vow
ijiwaru de yasashi sono umi no you na
When I leap into your heart, I take it
kokoro ni tobikondara uketomete
Harsh and kind, like that ocean
omosa ja
It's heavy
hakarenai konna omoi
These kinds of feelings you cannot weigh
kimi dake ni ima
Because I can only tell it to you now.
tsutaeru kara
You can only save yourself.
Oshino always said that.
You know that, don't you. Little missy.
It's a Western fairy tale.
In some place there lived one young man. A good young man.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
One day,
he met a wonderous
old man in the city.
The old man
asked that young man
to sell his shadow.
Shadow?
Yes. The shadow that comes
from your feet when you are lit by the sun.
"Ten gold coins" is what he asked for.
That young man sold it without hesitation. For ten gold coins.
"And?"
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
That young man didn't even think once
that his shadow had more worth than ten gold coins.
Well, wasn't he right?
Practically speaking, not having a shadow is hardly a disadvantage.
There isn't any constraint.
Oshino continued speaking
while increasingly gesturing.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
But in the end, it didn't go well:
the young man was persecuted by townspeople and family.
It was just out of place.
“It's weird for someone to not have a shadow,” they said.
Well, that's it.
It's just weird.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Well, shadow itself can be weird too, but not to have any shadow
is hundred times more weird. Like... something normal is missing.
So, Young man sold his normality for ten gold coins.
Silent
Voice
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
That young man looked for the mysterious old man in order to return his shadow
but no matter how hard he searched, no matter where he searched,
he couldn't find that old man, so it's said.
Used typeface for image : HGP mincho B
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
Episode 2
Are you going to help me?
（戦場ヶ原）助けてくれるんですか
I won't help you. I will, however, lend you my powers.
（忍野(おしの)）助けない　力は貸すけど
Oh, and please make a trip home.
そうだね　一旦 家に帰りなさい
When you get there, I ask that you cleanse your body with holy water and change into a set of pure clothes.
それで 身体を冷水で清めて
清潔な服に着替えて来てくれる？
Does meeting me back here around midnight sound all right?
夜中の零時ごろ もういっぺん
ここに集合ってことで いいかな？
I can do that, but...
（戦場ヶ原）いいですけれど
And the reward?
（戦場ヶ原）お礼は…
（忍野）うん？
Huh?
Don't play dumb.
（戦場ヶ原）とぼけないでください
You're not saying you'll help me for free, are you?
ボランティアで助けてくれる
というわけでは ないんでしょう？
Well... if it makes you feel better, I guess I can charge you.
まっ そのほうで
お嬢ちゃんの気が楽だっていうなら
もらっておくことにしよっか
How does 100,000 yen sound?
じゃ そうだね 10万円で
100,000 yen.
10万円…
You treat her extremely differently from how you treated me.
僕のときとは 随分 対応が違うな
Really?
そうだっけ？
As I recall, the price I quoted for the class representative was also 100,000 yen.
委員長ちゃんのときも
確か10万円だったと思うけれど
You asked me for a whopping 5,000,000 yen!
僕のときは
500万だったって言ってんだよ！
But that was a vampire, you know. It couldn't be helped.
（忍野）
吸血鬼だもん しかたないよ
Don't blame anything and everything on the vampire!
（阿良々木）
何でもかんでも安易に
吸血鬼のせいにするな！
Can you pay?
払える？
もちろん
Of course.
No matter what I might have to do.
どんなことをしてでも
Of course.
もちろん
（阿良々木）
う〜ん　10万円か…
A
Be careful with fire
One match leads to fire
100,000 yen, huh?
I've finished taking a shower.
（戦場ヶ原）
シャワー 済ませたわよ
Could you get out of the way?
そこを どいてちょうだい
服が取り出せないわ
I can't get to my clothes.
Clothes! Put on your clothes!
服を着ろ 服を！
That's exactly what I'm doing.
だから 今から着るのよ
I'm saying that you should have put something on before you stepped out!
（阿良々木）
最初から着てろって言ってんだ！
I forgot to carry them in with me.
（戦場ヶ原）
持って入るのを忘れていたのよ
Then at least cover yourself with a towel or something!
（阿良々木）
だったら
タオルで隠すとかしやがれ！
I don't want to do something that a poor person would do!
（戦場ヶ原）
嫌よ そんな貧乏くさいマネ
The first time that I've seen a girl completely nude...
（阿良々木）
女性の全裸を初めて見てしまった
Black scene
Animation Number 'none'
Pure clothes, huh?
（戦場ヶ原）清潔な服ね
Do you think he'd prefer white clothing?
白い服のほうが いいと思う？
（阿良々木）知らねえよ…
I don't know.
I don't have any bras or panties that don't have patterns.
（戦場ヶ原）ショーツとブラは
柄物しか持っていないの
I don't care!
知らねえよ！
Araragi-kun,
（戦場ヶ原）
阿良々木くん まさか あなた
You haven't gotten aroused from seeing me nude, have you?
私のヌードを見て
欲情したのではないでしょうね
Even if I have, it wouldn't be my fault!
（阿良々木）
仮に そうだったとしても
僕の責任じゃない！
Done. You can turn around.
（戦場ヶ原）
もういいわよ　こっちを向いても
I see. Seriously...
（阿良々木）そうかよ ったく…
What's your motive?!
（阿良々木）
何が目的なんだ お前は！
What?
（戦場ヶ原）何よ
This is a special service as a reward for today.
今日のお礼のつもりで
大サービスしてあげてるんだから
You should at least be happy.
ちょっとは喜びなさいよ
Be a little bit happy, will you?
ちょっとは喜びなさいよ！
I should be getting mad.
（阿良々木）
逆切れされた！
You should at least give me a critique as a courtesy.
（戦場ヶ原）
感想くらい言うのが
礼儀でしょう
A critique...?
（阿良々木）か… 感想って
Y-You have a nice figure... How's that?
い… いい体してるね とか？
Terrible.
（戦場ヶ原）最低
It's exactly why you will forever be a virgin.
そんなことだから
あなたは 一生 童貞なのよ
Forever?!
（阿良々木）
一生？
お前は未来から来た人なのか？
Did you come from the future?!
Please refrain from spitting.
（戦場ヶ原）
唾を飛ばさないでくれる？
童貞がうつるわ
I'll be infected by your virginity.
Like a man's virginity could spread to a woman!
女に童貞がうつるか！
Guys can't either.
Animation Number 103
Hold up... Come to think of it...
ていうか ちょっと待て
The topic is proceeding on the assumption that I am a virgin.
僕が童貞であることを前提に
話が進んでいるぞ
うん 確かに
偏見でものを言ったわね
It's true that my words are biased.
ハア…
分かってくれればいいんだ
I'm glad you realize that.
Just don't spit.
唾を飛ばさないで
素人童貞がうつるわ
Your amateurish virginity will infect me.
I admit it.
認めましょう　僕は童貞野郎です！
I am a virgin!
Don't worry.
（戦場ヶ原）心配しなくとも
I'll keep this a secret from Hanekawa-san.
羽川さんには
内緒にしておいてあげるのに
Why her?
羽川って？
Isn't she the girl you have a crush on?
彼女 阿良々木くんの
片恋(かたこい)相手じゃないの？
You guys talk frequently, don't you?
よく話しているでしょう？
That's incorrect.
（阿良々木）それは違う
That's just because Hanekawa is honestly the type that looks after others.
あれは単純に
羽川の面倒見がいいだけだ
"The most useless people are pitiful."
あいつは いちばんダメなヤツが
いちばん かわいそうで
"They will definitely be used."
不当に損をしているって
She always has such amusing misconceptions.
そんな愉快な勘違いを
しているんだ
That sure is an amusing misconception, isn't it?
それは本当に愉快な勘違いね
Even though the most useless people are just the most foolish.
いちばんダメなヤツは
いちばん愚かなだけなのに
No, I didn't say that much.
（阿良々木）
いや 僕は
そこまでは言ってません
It was written all over your face.
（戦場ヶ原）顔に書いてあるわ
No it wasn't.
書いてねえよ
Having predicted that you'd say that, I already wrote it on your face.
そう言うと思って
さっき書いておいたわ
No way in hell are you that well prepared!
（阿良々木）
そんな手回しがあり得るか！
（戦場ヶ原）
忍野さんのお世話になったのね？
Hanekawa-san was also helped by Oshino-san before as well, right?
羽川さんも
（阿良々木）うん まあな
You could say that, I guess.
（戦場ヶ原）ふうん
That's why I think he's more or less trustworthy.
（阿良々木）
だから 一応
信頼していいとは思うぜ
It's not just my testimony.
僕一人の証言じゃなく
羽川もそうだっていうんだから
Hanekawa says so, too.
（戦場ヶ原）そう…
I see.
However, Araragi-kun...
でもね 阿良々木くん
If I could believe him that easily, I would have been tricked countless times.
彼のことを おいそれと信じるには
私は 今まで何度も何度も
だまされ続けているわ
That's why I can never have such optimistic thoughts.
だから そんな楽天的なふうには
どうしたって ちっとも思えないの
You took the time to put it on; why remove it?
（阿良々木）
せっかく着たのに
なんで脱ぐんだよ
I forgot to dry my hair.
（戦場ヶ原）
髪を乾かすのを忘れていたわ
You... Could it be that you're just an idiot?
（阿良々木）
お前 ひょっとして
ただのバカなんじゃないか？
Please don't speak such rude words.
（戦場ヶ原）
失礼なことを
言わないでくれるかしら？
You could hurt my feelings.
私が傷ついたら大変じゃないの
You mentioned optimism just now, right?
（阿良々木）
さっき 楽天的って言ってたな
Isn't that how it goes?
（戦場ヶ原）そうじゃなくて？
Maybe.
（阿良々木）かもしんね
But being optimistic isn't a bad thing, is it?
でも いいんじゃねえの？
別に楽天的でも
It's not like you're doing anything bad.
悪いことをしてるわけじゃないし
It's also not like you're cheating either.
ズルしているわけでも
ないんだから
Not doing anything bad, huh?
悪いことを
しているわけじゃない… か
Isn't that so?
（阿良々木）だろ？
（戦場ヶ原）まあ そうね
That's true.
But...
でも…
Black scene
Animation Number 'none'
It may be considered a form of cheating.
Black scene
Animation Number 'none'
ズルは しているかも
Black scene
Animation Number 'none'
Huh?
（阿良々木）え？
（戦場ヶ原）何でもないわ
Nothing.
Say, Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）
ねえ 阿良々木くん
１つ聞いていい？
May I ask you something?
What did you mean when you said it's comparable to the pattern on the moon?
月の模様みたいって
どういうこと？
Huh? What are you talking about?
（阿良々木）え？ 何の話だ？
Didn't you say that to Oshino-san back then?
（戦場ヶ原）
言っていたじゃないの 忍野さんに
Oh, that?
ほら 月の模様って 日本からだと
It is said that when you see the moon in Japan, its patterns resemble rabbits pounding rice cakes.
うさぎが 餅をついているように
見えるけれど
Whereas abroad, a crab or a beautiful woman can be seen.
海外からだと 蟹(かに)だったり
美人の横顔だったりする
っていうから
Oh, is that so?
（戦場ヶ原）へえ そうなんだ
I'm surprised you know such useless things.
そんなくだらないことを
よく知っているわね
This is the first time since birth that I've admired you.
生まれて初めて
あなたに感心したわ
It's nothing.
（阿良々木）なあに
I'm just familiar with astronomy and cosmology.
僕は 天文学や宇宙科学には
詳しいんだよ
It's fine.
（戦場ヶ原）
いいのよ
私の前では格好つけなくとも
There's no need to act cool in front of me.
Besides, you don't know about anything else, do you?
どうせ それ以外は
何も知らないんでしょう？
Are you aware of what verbal abuse is?
言葉の暴力って知ってるか
You should tell that to the police officer in charge of verbal abuse.
A
Survival Hope!
Traditional Doll Deathhouse
Wife Drama Salon
Tomorrow is "The Retired Life"
Tsukamoto Kurogane
Police 24 hours
Save people who couldn't bear
verbal harassment
Present Masato Sanjo
1 o'clock show - Famous People /
Places of Hatsukoni homes
Flower of the Japanese white radish
Plants Activities
Around the World
Wrestling Children
Tomatoes Hot
Free Music
Hometo Search
（戦場ヶ原）
なら 言葉の警察を呼びなさいよ
お前…
Why, you...
You only want to show me that proud body of yours.
実は 自慢の肉体を
僕に見せびらかしたいだけなのか？
Proud body of mine?
（戦場ヶ原）
自慢の肉体だなんて
そんなに うぬぼれていないわ
I'm not that arrogant.
I'm just not used to wearing clothes.
服を着るのは得意じゃないの
重たいのよ
They're heavy.
But I didn't think you would be so knowledgeable, Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）
けれど 意外と学があるのね
阿良々木くん
I'm surprised.
びっくりしたわ
It might actually be possible that there is a brain inside your head.
ひょっとしたら 頭の中に脳みそが
入っているのかもしれないわね
（阿良々木）当たり前だろ
That's obvious.
Obvious?
（戦場ヶ原）当たり前って…
A creature like you having a brain residing in his skull...
あなたのような生物(せいぶつ)の頭蓋骨に
脳みそが入っているというのは
...is already a miracle in and of itself.
それはそれは
もう奇跡のような出来事なのよ？
You... think I am really stupid, don't you?
お前 僕の頭がすごく悪い
と思っているだろう
あっ！ なぜ気付いたの？
How did you know?
Seemed like she wanted to keep that hidden
Animation Number 167
You're actually expressing genuine shock!
真顔で驚かれた！
Because of my carelessness, Araragi-kun realized that his brain is slower than others'.
私のせいで 阿良々木くんが
自分の頭のお粗末さ加減に
気付いてしまった
I feel so guilty.
責任を感じるわ
Hey, wait a minute.
おい ちょっと待て
Is my stupidity level really that grave?
僕は そんな深刻なレベルの
頭の悪さなのか？
My standardized test score is seventy-four.
偏差値チェック 私 74
くっ… 僕 46
Mine's forty-six...
When rounded, it becomes zero.
四捨五入すればゼロね
Huh?
はあ？ ウソつけ ６だから…
Liar. Forty-six would round up to...
（阿良々木）
あっ！ お前 さては十の位を！
Hey, you rounded from the tens place!
How could you do that to my standardized test score?
僕の偏差値に何てことするんだ！
One hundred.
（戦場ヶ原）
100… 差をつけないと
勝った気がしないのよ
I can't grasp the sense of victory without expanding the difference.
You also rounded your own score from the tens place...
（阿良々木）
自分の数値も十の位を…
うん　決めたわ
I've decided.
If everything goes well, let's visit Hokkaido to eat crab.
（戦場ヶ原）
もしも 全てがうまくいったら
北海道へ蟹を食べにいきましょう
Well, I guess that would be fine...
（阿良々木）
まあ いいんじゃないのか？
You will be going as well.
（戦場ヶ原）あなたも行くのよ
Why?
（阿良々木）なんで？
Ah, don't you know?
（戦場ヶ原）
あら 知らなかったの？
Trip to Hokkaido.
Six days, seven nights.
All-you-can-eat crab.
Crab is very delicious.
蟹って とってもおししいのよ
A
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
Welcome to
Naoetsu’s
national
pride.
A
No vehicles beyond this point
protect
lives
Garbage collection
Combustible - Tue, Fri
Plastic - Wed
Resources, Damaged - Thu
PET Bottles - Wed
Don’t jump out
into the road
A
Left
Safety first
Mind the doors and windows
Entrance prohibited
A
Dangerous area. No entrance allowed
except for authorized personnel.
Toyama Constructions
A
Watch out above
Danger
Dangerous area. No entrance allowed except for authorized personnel.
Safety
Work
Area
Toyama
Construction
Danger
Entrance
prohibited
Danger
A
s
b
e
s
t
o
s
Wear masks
Suspended
Danger
DANGER
Watch
out
above
No entrance allowed except for authorized personnel
A
Entrance prohibited
no exceptions
Danger
Oshino-san, you were a priest?
（戦場ヶ原）
忍野さんって
神職の方だったんですか？
No, I'm not.
（忍野）いや 違うよ
Even though it was my specialization in university, I have not been employed by any shrine.
大学の学科は そうなんだけれど
神社に就職はしていない
I thought over a lot of things.
いろいろ思うところがあってね
Entrance
prohibited
うん　お嬢ちゃん
いい感じに清廉になっているよ
You look like you've been purified nicely, miss.
It is quite well done.
見事なもんだね
Just to confirm, are you wearing make-up?
一応 確認しておくけれど
お化粧は していない？
I thought it best not to, hence I did not put any on.
（戦場ヶ原）
しないほうがいいかと思って
していません
Right.
（忍野）そう
Your judgment is correct.
まっ とりあえず正しい判断だ
Has Araragi-kun taken a shower?
阿良々木くんも
シャワー 浴びてきたかい？
Yeah, I took a shower at Senjougahara's place.
（阿良々木）
ああ 戦場ヶ原に借りた
問題ないよ
No problem.
Wear
duty
ふうん
君は代わり映えしないねえ
You still haven't improved, have you?
Don't say such unnecessary things.
余計なこと言うな
DANGER
By the way, Oshino...
（阿良々木）しかし 忍野
Is this crab or whatever easy to exorcise?
蟹だか何だかって そんな簡単に
退治できるもんなのか？
Your way of thinking is really violent, Araragi-kun.
（忍野）
考え方が乱暴だなあ
阿良々木くんは
Did anything good happen?
何か いいことでも あったのかい？
Shinobu-chan and that nymphomaniac cat attacked you and that class representative out of malice...
忍(しのぶ)ちゃんや 色ボケ猫は
悪意と敵意を持って
阿良々木くんと委員長ちゃんを
襲ったわけだけれど
But that's not the case with the crab.
今回の蟹は そうじゃないんだから
What do you mean?
（阿良々木）そうじゃないって？
Didn't I say that the opponent is a god?
（忍野）
言ったろ？ 相手は神様なんだよ
As such, we are not going to exorcise it.
だから 退治するのではなく
今から僕たちはね
Starting now, we are going to pray.
神様にお願いするんだよ
Your attitudes must be respectful.
下手(したて)に出てね
Is it something that can be returned if prayed for?
お願いしたら それで
返してもらえるもんなのか？
Senjougahara's...
戦場ヶ原の
weight.
重み 体重は
Body mass.
Maybe?
（忍野）多分ね
They are not so stubborn as to reject desperate wishes from humans.
切実な人間の頼みを断るほど
彼らは頑(かたく)なじゃないさ
Though, gods are a bunch of careless beings.
それに神様っていうのは
結構 大ざっぱな連中なんだ
Careless, as in?
（阿良々木）大ざっぱって？
They don't care about the personal problems of humans.
（忍野）
人間 個々人のことなんて
どうでもいいんだよ
In fact, gods can't even differentiate between the age, gender, or weight of the three of us.
実際 神様の前じゃ
僕ら３人 年齢も性別も重みも
区別なんかつかないよ
Hey, is that crab still beside me?
（戦場ヶ原）ねえ あの蟹は
今も 私のそばにいますか？
Yeah, it's still right beside you.
そう そこにいるし どこにでもいる
But it's also everywhere.
If you want to summon it, you need to follow step-by-step procedures.
ただし ここに
降りてきてもらうためには
（忍野）手順が必要だけどね
（戦場ヶ原）あ…
A
Middle school second grade classroom
In charge:
Arashou Kinjou
Both of you, look down at the floor.
（忍野）２人とも 目を伏せて
Keep your heads down.
（忍野）頭を低くしてくれる？
（２人）え？
Huh?
This place is already right in front of the god.
神前だよ　ここはもう
（戦場ヶ原）え… 何ですか？
What's this?
Drinking sake seems to be able to shorten the distance to gods.
（忍野）お酒を飲むと
神様との距離を
縮めることができるそうだよ
I'm underage.
（戦場ヶ原）未成年です
It's not like you're drinking till you drop. Just take a sip.
（忍野）
酔うほどの量は飲まなくていいさ
ちっとだけ
Okay, you two.
さて…
Let's start by relaxing.
じゃあ リラックスするところから
始めよう
This position belongs to you.
ここは自分の場所だ
君がいて当たり前の場所
You're standing in your rightful position.
はい…
Yes.
Close your eyes while continuing to tilt your head.
頭を下げたまま
目を閉じて 数を数えよう
Begin counting.
One.
（忍野）一つ 二つ
Two.
Three.
三つ 四つ
Four.
Five.
五つ 六つ
Six.
七つ
Seven.
Eight.
八つ
Nine...
九つ
Have you calmed down?
落ち着いた？
Yes.
（戦場ヶ原）はい
All right, then answer my questions.
（忍野）
そう じゃあ 質問に答えてみよう
Question
Miss, what is your name?
お嬢ちゃん
君の名前は？
Senjougahara Hitagi.
（戦場ヶ原）
戦場ヶ原ひたぎ
Question 2
What is the name of the school that you're attending?
（忍野）
通っている学校は？
Naoetsu Private High School.
（戦場ヶ原）
私立直江津(なおえつ)高校
Question 3
（忍野）誕生日は？
When is your birthday?
July 7th.
（戦場ヶ原）７月７日
Question 4
Who is your favorite novelist?
（忍野）
いちばん好きな
小説家は？
Yumeno Kyuusaku.
Question
Could you tell us about an experience of failure you had as a child?
（忍野）
子供のころの失敗談を
聞かせてくれる？
I don't want to reveal that.
言いたくありません
Question 6
What is your favorite classical music?
（忍野）
好きな古典音楽は？
I'm not very interested in music.
（戦場ヶ原）
音楽は
あまり たしなみません
Question 7
How did you feel when you graduated from elementary school?
（忍野）
小学校を卒業するとき
どう思った？
I took it as nothing more than a transfer to middle school.
（戦場ヶ原）
単純に中学校に
移るだけだと思いました
I simply moved from one public school to another.
公立から公立へ
行くだけだったから
Question 8
What type of person was your first love?
（忍野）
初恋の男の子は
どんな子だった？
I don't want to reveal that.
（戦場ヶ原）
言いたくありません
Question 9
Up till now, what has been your most painful memory?
（忍野）
今までの人生で
いちばん
つらかった思い出は？
What's wrong?
（忍野）どうしたの？
Your most painful memory...
いちばん つらかった思い出
記憶について聞いているんだ
What I'm asking is that you recall your worst memory.
（戦場ヶ原）
お… お… お母さんが…
M-My mother...
Your mother?
（忍野）お母さんが
She got immersed in a cult.
悪い宗教に はまったこと
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
Is that all?
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
（忍野）それだけかい？
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
What do you mean "is that all?"
それだけって…
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
Continue.
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
（忍野）
言ってごらん
何があった？
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
What happened?
Animation Number 298
Answer the question
A-A high-ranking cult member came to my house.
（戦場ヶ原）
う… うちに
その宗教団体の幹部の人が
My mom brought him there.
お母さんに連れられて
やって来て
Brought him there... What happened next?
（忍野）やって来て どうした？
Hand
He claimed that it was a ritual...
（戦場ヶ原）
儀式だと言って 私を…
Hand
I...
わ… 私に
Demand adultery.
Animation Number 306
乱暴を
Demand adultery.
Animation Number 306
...was violated.
Demand adultery.
Animation Number 306
He... attempted to rape me.
私を… 犯そうとしたわ
I see.
（忍野）そうかい
You said that he attempted to rape you, meaning it didn't happen?
でも“犯そうと”ということは
未遂だったんだろう？
I used a spiked shoe beside me to hit him.
近くにあったスパイクで
殴ってやったわ
Stabbed
But... my mom did not come to my rescue.
でも お母さんは
私を助けてくれなかった
Mother
Return
（忍野）そして？
After that?
Because I injured the high-ranking cult member, my mom was...
（戦場ヶ原）
私が その幹部に
ケガをさせたせいで お母さんは…
M**her
A
Destruction
M**her
Your mom was punished, correct?
（忍野）
お母さんはペナルティを負った？
はい　でも 考えてしまうんです
Yes.
But I always find myself thinking about it.
If I hadn't resisted at that time, maybe my mother wouldn't have fallen into such a pathetic state.
もしも 私が あのとき
抵抗しなかったら
A
O
I
E
U
少なくとも こんなことには
ならなかったんじゃないかって
Then our relationship would not have been broken.
壊れなかったんじゃないかって
Then, miss, those are your feelings.
（忍野）
だったら それは
お嬢ちゃん 君の思いだ
Photograph
Animation Number 322B
No matter how heavy they are, they are things you must carry with you.
Photograph
Animation Number 322B
どんなに重かろうと
Photograph
Animation Number 322B
A
O
I
E
U
それは君が
背負わなくてはならないものだ
You can't push them onto someone else.
人任せにしちゃあ いけないね
Photograph
Animation Number 'none'
A
O
I
E
U
Pushing them onto someone else...
（戦場ヶ原）
人任せに… し…
Upper title
Animation Number 'none'
Lower title
Without looking away...
（忍野）
目を背けずに
目を開けて見てみよう
Upper title
Animation Number 'none'
Lower title
Open your eyes and take a look.
Upper title
Animation Number 'none'
Lower title
Upper title
Animation Number 'none'
Lower title
A
Crabs, part of the arthropod family, are decapod crustaceans
with short tails. They have two claws and four legs, a hard shell,
and crawl mainly sideways. There are many varieties of
freshwater and seawater crabs, large and small. There are
many that are edible. Though there are types of crabs
categorized as Japanese Spider Crabs and Coconut Crabs,
they are generally called crabs.
A
Can you see anything?
（忍野）何か見えるかい？
I see it.
み… 見えます　あのときと同じ…
It's the same as that time.
The same as that time.
あのときと同じ大きな蟹が
蟹が見える
A huge crab.
I can see a crab.
（忍野）そうかい
Is that so?
I can't see anything.
僕には 全く見えないがね
阿良々木くんは？
What about you Araragi-kun?
I can't see anything.
（阿良々木）何も見えない
But I see it very clearly.
で… でも
はっきりと見えます 私には
Is that so? Then...
（忍野）そう　だったら…
Then... isn't there something you need to say?
だったら 言うべきことが
あるんじゃないか？
Something I need to say?
言うべき… こと あっ
あっ 戦場ヶ原！
Senjougahara!
All right, fine.
（忍野）しかたがないな
Seriously, what an impatient god.
やれやれ せっかちな神さんだ
It's an energetic fellow, I must say.
気のいいヤツだよ 本当に
Did something good happen?
何か いいことでも あったのかな
（阿良々木）お… おい　忍野
Hey, Oshino!
I got it.
（忍野）
分かっているよ 方針変更だ
やむをえん
Change of plans.
I have to do this now.
Take that!
よっ こらっ せっと
In the end, this is still a question of self-reflection.
（忍野）
結局 こういうのって
心の持ちようの問題だからさ
If praying does not work, and words are ineffective...
お願いできないなら
言葉が通じないなら
...what's left is to fight.
戦争しかないのさ
（阿良々木）でも…
But...
Regardless, if it's disposed of like that...
（忍野）
まあ このまま
潰しちゃったところで
...according to procedure, this problem will be solved.
形の上では解決するからさ
For this case, I say that's one possible solution.
この際 それもありかなって
A possible solution?
（阿良々木）あ… ありかなって
I generally hate crabs...
（忍野）
僕は 蟹が
とてつもなく嫌いなんだよ
...because they're hard to eat.
食べにくいからね
（戦場ヶ原）待って
Wait.
Please wait, Oshino-san.
待ってください 忍野さん
Wait?
（忍野）
待つって
待つって何をさ？ お嬢ちゃん
Wait for what, miss?
Just now, I was merely frightened.
さっきは驚いただけだから
A
Middle school second grade classroom
I will do this properly.
ちゃんと できますから
I can do it myself.
自分で できるから
ふうん
A
Middle school second grade classroom
Then help yourself.
（忍野）
じゃあ どうぞ　やってごらん
Give it a try.
I'm sorry.
（戦場ヶ原）ごめんなさい
And... thank you very much.
それから ありがとうございました
But you've done enough.
でも もういいんです
Because those are my thoughts, my feelings, and my memories.
それは私の気持ちで
私の思いで 私の記憶ですから
I will carry them myself.
私が背負います
They are things that I should not have lost.
なくしちゃ いけないものでした
I beg you, may I...
お願いします
どうか 私に
私の重みを返してください
May I please have my weight back?
May I please have my mother back?
どうか お母さんを
私に返してください
A flashback
Animation Number 390
It seems that when Senjougahara's mother got immersed in the cult,
（阿良々木）
戦場ヶ原の母親が
悪徳宗教に はまったのは
Senjougahara was a fifth grader.
戦場ヶ原が
小学５年生のときだったらしい
A
I
U
E
O
Open the mind’s eye
She had a serious illness at that time.
そのころ 戦場ヶ原は
ひどい大病を患った
Red animation
Animation Number 'none'
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
Right hand of the Devil
Torso
Head
Left hand of God
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
She went to cry out.
Beloved daughter's arms,
legs will be disfigured.
Animation Number 393
A
O
I
E
U
Because of her daughter's illness, Senjougahara's mother wanted to seek spiritual assurance.
娘の病気にあたり
戦場ヶ原の母親は
心のよりどころを求めた
A
Operating
そして…
Then...
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to drink medicine and
grate apples as soon as possible
Animation Number 396
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Need to cut
If it isn’t cut
Need to connect
If it doesn’t connect
Ah, busy
Busy
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
Cherry flower, Flower, Flower,
Tooth, Bloomed, Bloomed
Animation Number 393
...Senjougahara managed to survive a major surgical operation.
戦場ヶ原は大手術の結果
九死に一生を得たそうだ
A
Fervently
But her mother became increasingly immersed in the cult.
だが それによって母親は
ますます
宗教に のめり込んでしまった
Flashback
A
Praying
After that, the relationship between Senjougahara and her mother became strained.
戦場ヶ原は
母親と不仲になったそうだ
It seems that she stopped talking to her mother during her middle school years.
中学生になってからは
ほとんど 口を利かなかったらしい
Do it like a beast
Animation Number 402B
そして…
Do it like a beast
Animation Number 402B
And then...
Do it like a beast
Animation Number 402B
Just before graduation from middle school, an incident occurred.
中学卒業を間近にして事は起きた
A
Desire to molest
a girl
Perverted sexual desire
Beast
Palm of the hand
o
Strange
A
O
I
E
U
This resulted in...
その結果—
Destruction
...the breaking up of the family.
家庭は崩壊してしまった
Black scene
Animation Number 'none'
It became irreparable.
破局した
STOP
It was then that Senjougahara met a crab.
そして 戦場ヶ原は行き遭った
１匹の蟹に
End of flashback
Animation Number 414
A weight crab... That sort of thing, Araragi-kun...
（忍野）
おもし蟹(がに)ってのはね 阿良々木くん
is also called an emotion god.
だからつまり “おもいし神(かみ)”
ってことなんだよね
Also, a bond is formed through a combination of feelings and protection.
Middle school second grade classroom
また“思(おも)い出(と)しがみ”
つまり しがらみってことでも
あるんだ
That is to say, when Senjougahara met the crab,
（阿良々木）
つまり 蟹に行き遭ったとき
戦場ヶ原は
母親へのしがらみを切ったのだ
she cut all ties to her mother so she could stop feeling troubled regarding such matters.
母親のことで
思い悩むことをやめた
She stopped thinking about those feelings, and therefore lost weight.
思うのをやめた
重みをなくしたのだ
She chose to cheat herself.
自ら進んでズルをした
Middle school second grade classroom
It actually isn't such a bad thing.
別に
悪いことじゃないんだけどねえ
This case especially, since even if she gets her feelings back,
特に今回の場合
今更 思いを取り戻したところで
her mother won't come back and the family will remain broken.
母親が帰ってくるわけでも
崩壊した家庭が
再生するわけでもない
Even then, even so...
（阿良々木）
それなのに それでも
Nostalgic memories of family
Neck
Hand
Nostalgic memories of family
Because of that, Senjougahara Hitagi wanted to take them back.
それゆえに 戦場ヶ原ひたぎは
返してほしかった
Nostalgic memories of family
She begged to get them back.
返してほしがった
Nostalgic memories of family
Those unbearable feelings of her mother, memories, and frustrations.
もう どうしようもない
母親の思い出を 記憶と悩みを
Nostalgic memories of family
忍野の言うとおり
何も変わらないのだろうけれど
Nostalgic memories of family
Like what Oshino said, maybe nothing will change.
It's not like nothing can be changed.
Nostalgic memories of family
（戦場ヶ原）
何も変わらない
なんてことはないわ
Nostalgic memories of family
Besides, it isn't a futile effort.
それに 決して
ムダでもなかったのよ
At least I gained an important friend.
少なくとも
大切な友達が１人 出来たのだから
Who are you referring to?
誰のことだ？
You.
（戦場ヶ原）あなたのことよ
（阿良々木）えっ！
Thank you, Araragi-kun.
（戦場ヶ原）
ありがとう 阿良々木くん
I'm really grateful to you.
私は あなたに
とても感謝しているわ
I apologize for all my actions up till now.
今までのこと 全部 謝ります
Even though saying such a thing now is shameless, if we can get along from now on...
図々(ずうずう)しいかもしれないけれど
これからも仲良くしてくれたら
私 とてもうれしいわ
I'll be very happy.
All right brother, it's morning now!
（火憐(かれん)）兄ちゃん！ 朝だぞ コラ！
It's about time you woke up.
（月火(つきひ)）
いいかげんに
起きないとダメだよ
I just went to sleep...
さっき寝たばっかりなのに
Oh, you were out all night, again?
あ〜 さては
また夜更かししてやがったな！
Seriously.
（２人）もう！
You're the only person who hasn't had breakfast yet, brother.
（月火）
朝ご飯 食べてないのは
お兄ちゃんだけだよ！
That's right, bro—
But still, my body feels heavy.
（阿良々木）
しかし 体がだるい
熱でもあるみたいだ
Do I have a fever or something?
I might as well mention it.
ちなみに僕の体重は55キロ でも…
My weight is 55 Kg.
But...
Hey, hey.
I see.
なるほど　神様ってのは
確かに大ざっぱな連中らしい
Gods really are careless creatures.
Bakemonogatari
Crab
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Crab
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Crab
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Crab
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
Bakemonogatari
Crab
Hitagi Crab, Part Two
CONTINUED NEXT TIME
I'm Karen.
（火憐）火憐だぜ！
（月火）月火だよ！
I'm Tsukihi.
When you say jungle-gyms nowadays...
（月火）
ジャングルジムって言うじゃん
（火憐）
私も言ったことある！
I've said it before!
（月火）
言い過ぎじゃないかな
Maybe you've said too much.
（火憐）言い過ぎって？
（月火）ジャングルて
Too much?
What do you mean by "jungle"?
（火憐）
ジャングル… じゃないな
It's not a jungle.
What about gym?
（月火）ジムて
（火憐）ジムでも ねえや
It's not a gym either.
That's false advertisement!
（月火）
イメージ操作だよ
Then can they name it so you can be happy?
（火憐）
じゃ どんな名前が正しいんだ？
（月火）
“鉄棒スペシャル”とかが
いいんじゃないかな
Maybe something like "Despair Special"?
（火憐）
すさまじそう！
That's seriously sounds pretty bad!
Then once again, let's start the preview riddle.
（月火）
では ここで予告編クイズ！
（火憐）
クイズ！
Riddle.
You're a bus driver.
（月火）
あなたはバスの運転手です
（火憐）
まさか 私が
バスの運転手だったとは！
I can't believe I'm the bus driver!
The three of us rode it in the first episode!
（月火）
最初の駅で３人 乗りました！
（火憐）
ノリノリだぜ！
Yep, we rode it!
What is the name of the person who drives your bus?
（月火）
さて バスの運転手の名前は
何でしょう！
Don't go too fast!
（火憐）
はしょり過ぎだあ！
Next episode: Mayoi Snail Part 1.
Next Time
Mayoi Snail Part 1
（火憐・月火）
次回「まよいマイマイ
其ノ壹(そのいち)」
All right, the answer is your name.
（月火）
はい　それが あなたの名前です
（火憐）
手品っぽく締めた！
You made it like a magic show.